<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PHPStorm | naxoc.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://naxoc.net/blog/categories/phpstorm/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://naxoc.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-08T14:38:27+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://naxoc.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Camilla Krag Jensen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Color schemes and productivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2013/11/10/color-schemes-and-productivity/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T13:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2013/11/10/color-schemes-and-productivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost all programmers have a color scheme or theme in their terminal and their code editor. Some people actually turns syntax highlighting off, but I will never understand that. To me &ndash; code is something that lives on a black or dark background and has syntax colors. I have only ever used a white background color scheme back when I was using Eclipse 8 years ago. And probably because I couldn&rsquo;t figure out how to set another color scheme than the one that comes with Eclipse.</p>

<p>Lately I have been really bothered by reflections in my glossy screen om my MBP and my Apple Cinema Display (I know &ndash; first world problem). In the afternoon all I could really see was me &ndash; like I was looking in a mirror. While that is very enjoyable it is not the way to get work done, so I set out to find a color scheme that would make it easier to see what I am working on and not myself so much. In that process I found out that I am super sensitive to changes in my editor work setup. Change the colors a little and I have a hard time reading through code fast. It is weird and a little bit stupid that it is so, but I can&rsquo;t help it. It takes me about 2 weeks to get reasonably comfortable with changes to a color scheme.</p>

<p>This blog post is really just a listing and some screen shots of the color schemes I like. And let me tell you right now: there is no dark background color scheme that solves the glare problem &ndash; I tried tons of them and none of them are magic. Moving your chair or source of light solves some of the glare problems, but if Apple would just go back to offering a non-glare version it would be a lot easier.</p>

<h2>The ones I like</h2>

<h3>Desert theme</h3>

<p>I really like the &ldquo;Desert&rdquo; color scheme that comes with Vim as one of the default color schemes.
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/vim-desert.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/vim-desert.png</a>" title="&lsquo;Vim desert color scheme&rsquo;" >
The only thing I find a little annoying is the hysterically yellow line numbers. I have put this line in my .gvimrc to tone down line numbers after the color scheme is applied:
<code>vim
hi LineNr guifg=grey50 guibg=grey20
</code>
That is better:
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/desert-grey-numbers.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/desert-grey-numbers.png</a>" title="&lsquo;Vim desert theme with grey line numbers&rsquo;" >
I haven&rsquo;t found a desert color scheme for PHPStorm yet. I also don&rsquo;t really like to use it in the terminal, so I guess the desert theme is a Vim thing for me.</p>

<h3>Tomorrow</h3>

<p>In both the terminal and PHPStorm I use the <a href="https://github.com/chriskempson/tomorrow-theme">Tomorrow theme</a>. It comes with support for a ton of different applications and is really well thought out. I started using this one because it has a white background version too. So much like the popular <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized</a> theme it can use the same colors on light and dark background.
In the terminal I mainly use Tomorrow Night Eighties and in PHPStorm I switch between Tomorrow Night Eighties and just plain Tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here is the dark version (Tomorrow Night Eighties).
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/tomorrow-night-eighties-phpstorm.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/tomorrow-night-eighties-phpstorm.png</a>" title="&lsquo;Tomorrow Night Eighties in PHPStorm&rsquo;" >
And here is the light version (Tomorrow).
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/tomorrow-phpstorm.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/tomorrow-phpstorm.png</a>" title="&lsquo;Tomorrow theme in PHPStorm&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I still mostly use the dark version, but when glare becomes too much I can pretty comfortably switch to the light version and still get stuff done. It is crazy how sensitive I am to having the colors be recognizable.</p>

<h2>Darcula</h2>

<p>This is the color scheme that comes with the look and feel for PHPStorm called Darcula. I think it is really good looking and I can use it &ndash; but only if there is not too much light. It is a little on the low contrast side.
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/darcula.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/color-scheme/darcula.png</a>" title="&lsquo;Darcula theme&rsquo;" ></p>

<h2>The one I don&rsquo;t like so much</h2>

<h3>Solarized</h3>

<p>I realize that all code snippets on my blog use solarized. It is mainly because I haven&rsquo;t taken the time to change it. It really is not as simple as you would think in Octopress. Ironically &ndash; on the documentation site for Octopress solarized is not used. I haven&rsquo;t figured out what theme it using. Maybe it is solarized without the yellow background and just plain white.</p>

<p>Anyway. No reason the hate on solarized. So many people use it and love it. I just happen to think that the dark version has almost zero contrast and the yellow version makes me want to pee.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up a file watcher for Compass in PHPStorm]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2013/10/06/setting-up-a-file-watcher-for-compass-in-phpstorm/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-06T20:55:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2013/10/06/setting-up-a-file-watcher-for-compass-in-phpstorm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>EDIT: <em>It seems that the version 7 early access now has a file watcher preset for Compass &ndash; nice work JetBrains! The part about scope from this blog post is still useful to you if you are on PHPStorm 7 though.</em></p>

<p>I started using PHPStorm about 6 months ago and while it is an extremely awesome and powerful IDE there are just so many things you can set up and configure. I have to admit that for the first couple of months I pretty much used PHPStorm just like I did Vim and not using any of the many configurable things except for the debugger. I am slowly venturing into playing around with setting more stuff up, and I thought I would share this one because it took me a while to get right.</p>

<p>It is super simple to use the <a href="http://compass-style.org/">Compass compiler</a> from the command line and I always have. But PHPStorm can compile your .scss files into .css on the fly so why not take advantage of that.</p>

<p>So here is what I did. The settings assume that you use something that resembles the default settings in a Compass project with a folder for the scss files and the css being output to another folder called something like &ldquo;stylesheets&rdquo; or &ldquo;css&rdquo; (could be anything really). You also need to have <a href="http://compass-style.org/install/">Compass installed on your machine</a>.</p>

<ol>
<li>In the PHPStorm settings, go to &ldquo;File Watchers&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Click the plus to add a watcher and choose SCSS.</li>
<li>Edit the settings to look like the ones on the screenshot. Where Compass is installed on your machine may not be in /usr/bin/compass like it is on mine, but you can use the command <code>whereis compass</code> from your command line to figure out where compass is. The output path is &ldquo;stylesheets&rdquo; for me for this particular project, but you shold edit that to whatever your project has named the css output folder.</li>
</ol>


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/compass-phpstorm.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/compass-phpstorm.png</a>" title="&lsquo;Settings in PHPStorm&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Note that I have created a &ldquo;scope&rdquo; called Theme. Scopes in PHPStorm are parts of your project that you would like included or excluded in things like searches and settings like this Compass setup. There is no reason for PHPStorm to listen for changes to your module files if your theme folder is where you have your Compass project. So if you click the button with the three dots at the scope field you can setup PHPStorm to only look where it is relevant. I use scopes a lot to cut down on how long searches take, so setting up a few scopes for each project is time well spent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
