<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cli | naxoc.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://naxoc.net/blog/categories/cli/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://naxoc.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-02T14:24:57+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://naxoc.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Camilla Krag Jensen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syntax highlighting commands with Zsh]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2014/02/02/syntax-highlighting-commands-with-zsh/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-02T13:48:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2014/02/02/syntax-highlighting-commands-with-zsh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started using zsh about a year ago after having resisted it with a passion.
My main worry was that I would &ldquo;forget how to bash&rdquo; and be lost on various servers I log in to. While there are some nifty things I have gotten a little too used to in zsh, I don&rsquo;t think it has been a big problem.</p>

<p>One thing that visually tells me that I am in zsh and not bash is that my zsh terminal syntax highlights as I type. Yes, you read that correctly. If you are not familiar with the <a href="https://github.com/zsh-users/zsh-syntax-highlighting">zsh-syntax-highlighting</a> prepare to have your mind blown.</p>

<p>When you are typing a command you get a yellow color:</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-1.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-1.png</a>"></p>

<p>Then when you have typed something that actually is a command you get green:</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-2.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-2.png</a>"></p>

<p>When you make a typo you get red:</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-3.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-3.png</a>"></p>

<p>It also makes correctly quoted strings yellow. I find that a nice help too:</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-4.png">https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/157691/cdn/naxocnet/zsh/zsh-syntax-4.png</a>"></p>

<p>On the <a href="https://github.com/zsh-users/zsh-syntax-highlighting">Github project</a> readme there are instructions for installing the plugin.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Format json output from cUrl neatly]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2013/11/22/format-json-output-from-curl-neatly/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T14:27:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2013/11/22/format-json-output-from-curl-neatly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a short simple tip to read json output from curl in a neat formatted way:</p>

<p>Pipe the output to Python like this:
<code>
curl "http://url.to.call?args=hi" | python -mjson.tool
</code></p>

<p>This will prettify the output and make json much more readable when testing webservices. It also validates the json, so if it contains errors you will get a warning.</p>

<p>It works with Python 2.6 and higher and you can find more info at the <a href="http://docs.python.org/2/library/json.html">Python docs page</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using specific versions of formula with Homebrew]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2012/06/05/using-specific-versions-of-formula-with-homebrew/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T13:54:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2012/06/05/using-specific-versions-of-formula-with-homebrew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have my LAMP stack and other things set up on my mac with the wonderful <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew">Homebrew</a>.</p>

<p>I recently did a <code>brew upgrade</code> on my system and it seemed that everything went smooth. But when I later ran PHP from the command line I got this error:
<code>
PHP Warning:  PHP Startup: Unable to load dynamic library '/usr/local/Cellar/memcached-php/2.0.1/memcached.so' - dlopen(/usr/local/Cellar/memcached-php/2.0.1/memcached.so, 9): Library not loaded: /usr/local/lib/libmemcached.9.dylib
  Referenced from: /usr/local/Cellar/memcached-php/2.0.1/memcached.so
  Reason: image not found in Unknown on line 0
</code></p>

<p>I poked around in my php.ini to see if the wrong file was being included or something like that, but it turned out that I had upgraded to a newer version of libmemcached than the one memcached was using. So I needed to downgrade libmemcached. Here is how to switch to any version available with Homebrew:</p>

<ol>
<li>
<code>brew versions libmemcached</code>
</li>
<li>
Find and note the version number you want. In my case I wasn't sure, so I just went with the second newest and that worked.
</li>
<li>
<code>brew switch libmemcached 1.0.4</code>
</li>
</ol>


<p>Change the version number and the formula above to whatever makes sense for what you are doing.</p>

<p>The example above is using a command that is an <a href="https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/wiki/External-Commands">external command</a> for Homebrew. It works super fast and is easy to use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving an iTunes Library]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2011/05/11/moving-an-itunes-library/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-11T15:22:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2011/05/11/moving-an-itunes-library</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are moving an iTunes library to a new mac it will go smooth if the user login is the same. So if I move my iTunes library from an old machine where it was located in <code>/Users/ckj/iTunes</code> to a new machine where it is gonna go in <code>/Users/ckj/iTunes</code> &ndash; I have no problems. But if I changed to another username on the new machine &ndash; all the paths in the iTunes Library.xml file will not be correct anymore. I have moved libraries so many times now and I thought I would share a really quick way to fix the iTunes Library.xml file to reflect the correct user directory.</p>

<p>If you use the built-in command line tool called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sed">sed</a>, you can type one line in the terminal and be done. Let’s say I was moving from a mac with a user directory called &ldquo;ckj&rdquo; to another machine with a user directory called &ldquo;naxoc&rdquo;. All I would have to do in the terminal would be this:</p>

<ol>
<li>cd to the iTunes folder in the user directory you are moving to.</li>
<li>Enter this: <code>sed -i "" -e "s,Users/ckj,Users/naxoc,g" files iTunes\ Library.xml</code></li>
</ol>


<p>Note the funky syntax with the <code>-i ""</code> This is a mac quirck in sed. I found some info on it <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2320564/variations-of-sed-between-osx-and-gnu-linux">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
