<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: images | naxoc.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://naxoc.net/blog/categories/images/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://naxoc.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-07T21:05:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://naxoc.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Camilla Krag Jensen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding unused images in your website code]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.net/2013/10/28/finding-unused-images-in-your-website-code/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-28T21:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.net/2013/10/28/finding-unused-images-in-your-website-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was doing a lot of changes to CSS files today &ndash; mainly deleting a whole lot of stuff. I wanted to see if there were image files that were referenced by CSS that were no longer in use, so I wrote this naïve little script that loops through all image files it finds in the dir you give it to see if there are references to the image files.</p>

<p>If you have <a href="https://github.com/ggreer/the_silver_searcher">The Silver Searcher</a> (ag) installed the script is much faster. Without Silver Searcher the script uses grep. If you don&rsquo;t know Silver Searcher go check it out &ndash; it is super fast.</p>

<p>``` sh</p>

<h1>!/bin/bash</h1>

<p>DIR=.
if [ -n &ldquo;$1&rdquo; ]
then
  DIR=$1
fi</p>

<h1>Find image files in.</h1>

<p>FILES=<code>find $DIR -type f | grep ".*\.\(jpg\|gif\|png\|jpeg\)"</code></p>

<h1>Default searcher is grep. If Silver Searcher is installed, use that.</h1>

<p>SEARCHER=&lsquo;grep -r -l &rsquo;
if command -v ag
then
  # Sweet! Let&rsquo;s use Silver Searcher.
  SEARCHER=&lsquo;ag -l &rsquo;
fi</p>

<h1>Loop over image files.</h1>

<p>for f in $FILES
do
  if [[ -f $f ]]
  then</p>

<pre><code>name=$(basename $f)
found=$($SEARCHER $name $DIR)
if [[ -z $found ]]
then
  echo $f
fi
</code></pre>

<p>  fi
done
```
<a href="https://gist.github.com/naxoc/7203765">Gist is here</a> &ndash; I find that the gist plugin for Octopress is  broken.</p>

<h2>How to use the script</h2>

<ol>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use windows.</li>
<li>Download the gist and put it somewhere in your project.</li>
<li>cd to the script in your command line and go <code>chmod u+x unused-images.sh</code></li>
<li>Run the script by going <code>sh unused-images.sh</code> or <code>/.unused-images.sh</code>. If you pass a directory as an argument you will search in that dir only. If you don&rsquo;t pass an argument the script will search in the dir it is in, so be a little bit careful with doing that in a directory that contains thousands of files.</li>
</ol>


<p>The script outputs the images that have no references. So if you feel courageous you can delete the unused image files by piping the output to xargs and delete:
<code>
./unused-images.sh themes | xargs rm
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
