<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PHP | naxoc.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://naxoc.github.io/blog/categories/php/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://naxoc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-23T23:30:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://naxoc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Camilla Krag Jensen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using specific versions of formula with Homebrew]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.github.io/2012/06/05/using-specific-versions-of-formula-with-homebrew/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T13:54:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.github.io/2012/06/05/using-specific-versions-of-formula-with-homebrew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have my LAMP stack and other things set up on my mac with the wonderful <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew">Homebrew</a>.</p>

<p>I recently did a <code>brew upgrade</code> on my system and it seemed that everything went smooth. But when I later ran PHP from the command line I got this error:
<code>
PHP Warning:  PHP Startup: Unable to load dynamic library &lsquo;/usr/local/Cellar/memcached-php/2.0.1/memcached.so&rsquo; &ndash; dlopen(/usr/local/Cellar/memcached-php/2.0.1/memcached.so, 9): Library not loaded: /usr/local/lib/libmemcached.9.dylib
  Referenced from: /usr/local/Cellar/memcached-php/2.0.1/memcached.so
  Reason: image not found in Unknown on line 0
</code></p>

<p>I poked around in my php.ini to see if the wrong file was being included or something like that, but it turned out that I had upgraded to a newer version of libmemcached than the one memcached was using. So I needed to downgrade libmemcached. Here is how to switch to any version available with Homebrew:</p>

<ol>
<li>
<code>brew versions libmemcached</code>
</li>
<li>
Find and note the version number you want. In my case I wasn't sure, so I just went with the second newest and that worked.
</li>
<li>
<code>brew switch libmemcached 1.0.4</code>
</li>
</ol>


<p>Change the version number and the formula above to whatever makes sense for what you are doing.</p>

<p>The example above is using a command that is an <a href="https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/wiki/External-Commands">external command</a> for Homebrew. It works super fast and is easy to use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pet peeve #1 - the comparison operator]]></title>
    <link href="http://naxoc.github.io/2010/12/10/pet-peeve-number-1-the-comparison-operator/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-10T14:27:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://naxoc.github.io/2010/12/10/pet-peeve-number-1-the-comparison-operator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a lot of pet peeves when it comes to programming, databases, web content, food, beer, and, well just about everyting. I am thinking of making a series of pet peeves here on this site. Some will seem like plain rants, and others will be more like tips.</p>

<p>When making comparisons, switch the order of the things you compare like this:
<code>php
if ('book' == $node-&gt;type) {
// Stuff happens.
}
</code>
You might think why? And that looks weird! Yes, it does look a little weird. But I do this to not accidentially assign the $node->type the value I am comparing it with. It is hell to find an error like this when debugging:
<code>php
if ($node-&gt;type = 'book') {
// Stuff happens whether you like it or not.
}
</code>
See what happened? I only put one = instead of two. PHP will not complain about this, I will just not get what I expect. If I had switched the items, PHP would have complained as I tried to assign an object to a non-variable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
